Wilton Historical Society Neighborhoods and Old Houses Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
Wilton Historical Society Neighborhoods and Old Houses Collection
Circa 1710-2010
Wilton Historical Society (Wilton, Conn.)
NEI
9 linear feet; 3 drawers
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
The Wilton Historical Society Neighborhoods and Old Houses Collection contains draft survey forms, index photographs, research notes, and other documentation relating (for houses) to date of construction, ownership history, major renovations, and relocations, and (for neighborhoods) dates of settlement, the names of founding and notable residents, prevailing economic activities and local businesses, the origins of local names, and the history of local roads. The information available for individual houses and neighborhoods varies widely. The earliest items date to the 1730s, but the bulk of the collection is mid- to late twentieth century.
Restrictions
Collection open for research.
History
1. Wilton Historical Society Neighborhoods and Old Houses Collection
The Wilton Historical Society, founded in 1938, has collected materials and sponsored research relating to individual Wilton houses, particularly colonial and Victorian structures. Additions have been made by Carol Russell, Wilton Historical Society Archivist and Wilton Town Historian. Much of the material in the collection are the notes and draft reports of local researchers (notably Malcolm Hunt of the Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn.) and architectural historians (such as Mary McCahon, who headed the 1989 Cultural Resource Survey of Wilton). In conjunction with a new historical resource survey in 2017, the Wilton Historical Society Old Houses and Neighborhoods Collection will be expanding to include historically important, architecturally significant, and particularly well-preserved Wilton houses from the 1920s through the 1940s.
2. Wilton History Room
The Wilton History Room is a unique collaboration between the Wilton Historical Society (WHS) and the Wilton Library Association (WLA). Compiled beginning in 1938, the archival collections of the Wilton Historical Society had been stored in the 18th century Fitch House. In 1980, the officers and trustees of the WHS, in conversation with the director and board members of the WLA, determined that a climate controlled space, improved organization, and better public accessibility were necessary; and so in January 1984 they established a home for the collection in the Wilton Library. Organization of the collections was supported by the Cudlipp Memorial Fund and undertaken by Carol Russell. The Wilton Historical Society has retained its ownership, while the Wilton Library maintains the collections, and provides access and assistance to patrons.
The Wilton History Room is one of the most complete, organized, and well-staffed historical research facilities, for a town of our size, in Fairfield County. It is supported by the WHS, the WLA, The Russell Fund, The History Room Fund, local non-profit organizations, individual donors, and community volunteers.
Today, the original archival collections of the WHS take up half of the Wilton History Room. Another quarter are library items. The collected papers of local organizations comprise the remainder: Cannon Grange, Children's Theater, Daughters of the American Revolution, Hurlbutt Street School House Association, Kiwanis Club, League of Women Voters, Rotary Club, Town Association, Weir Farm Stewardship Committee, Wilton Garden Club, Wilton Land Conservation Trust, Wilton Library, Wilton Playshop, Wilton Woman's Club, and more.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Wilton Historical Society Neighborhoods and Old Houses Collection contains architectural and historical information about Wilton's old houses and early neighborhoods. The oldest Wilton houses documented in the collection date to the early 1700s, when colonial structures were first built here by land proprietors and farmers from Norwalk. The bulk of Wilton houses in the collection, however, were built between the mid-1700s and the mid- to late 1800s. New additions to the collection, for historically and/or architecturally significant or particularly well-preserved houses built between the 1920s and the 1940s, are being made with the assistance of architectural historians conducting a new historical resource survey of Wilton.
Neighborhoods in the collection include: Bald Hill, Belden Hill, Cannondale, Chestnut Hill, Chicken Street, Comstock Ridge, Cottage Row, Danbury Road, Drum Hill, Dumplin Hill, Georgetown, Glen Hill, Grumman Hill, Hurlbutt, Kent, Nod Hill, Olmstead Hill, Pimpewaug, Prink's Plain, Ridgefield Road, Seir Hill, Sharp Hill, and Wilton Center.
Roads -- along with their select associated houses -- in the collection include: Belden Hill, Cannon, Cedar, Center, Chestnut Hill, Chicken, Church, Cottage Row, Danbury, DeForest, Drum Hill, East Meadow, Grumman Hill, Hubbard, Honey Hill, Hurlbutt, Kensett, Lover's Lane, Millstone, Mountain, Newtown Turnpike, Nod Hill, Old Belden, Old Boston, Old Mill, Old Ridgefield, Olmstead Hill, Own Home, Partrick, Pimpewaug, Pond, Ridgefield, Ruscoe, Scribner, Seeley, Seir Hill, Sharp Hill, Skunk, Sturges Ridge, West Church, West Meadow, Westport, Whipstick, and Wolfpit.
Arrangement
Collection materials are in folders arranged alphabetically by road name or neighborhood. The folders are stored in filing cabinet drawers.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Architectural surveys.; Historic buildings.; Homes.; Neighborhoods.; Roads.
Related Collections
Researchers interested in the history, locations, and boundaries of Wilton family properties and homes, or in Wilton neighborhoods, roads, and place-names, should also consult the Wilton History Room's other collections, particularly Maps and Manuscripts. Property histories of select Wilton families and individuals are narrated in Robert Russell's Wilton, Connecticut: Three Centuries of People, Places, and Progress. The Card File is also helpful in locating specific family names in the Norwalk Land Records. Finally, there are a number of pamphlets available in the History Room that researchers into Wilton neighborhoods and old houses will find useful, notably the three volume Annals of Wilton series published by the Wilton Historical Society between 1940 and 1971, and another published by the Junior League of Stamford-Norwalk for the 1978-1980 architectural survey, Wilton Architecturally Speaking (1980).
Separated Material
Select additional information as well as a large collection of artifacts drawn from many of the houses in the Wilton Historical Society Neighborhoods and Old Houses Collection may be seen at the Wilton Historical Society Museum. Legal documents after 1802 relating to property and house ownership and usage rights, including deeds and titles, are held in Wilton's Town Clerk's Office. Documentation prior to 1802 may be found in Norwalk.
- 1. Houses
  - Houses by address and name
    - 45 Belden Hill Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 463)
    - 67 Belden Hill Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 465)
    - 324 Belden Hill Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 540b)
    - 379 Belden Hill Road, undated; Built circa 1791. (Cabinet 2, Folder 544)
    - 358 Belden Hill Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 541b)
    - 311 Belden Hill Road - Benajah Gilbert house, undated; Built 1851. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 540a)
    - 332 Belden Hill Road - Benedict house, undated; Built circa 1790. (Cabinet 2, Folder 541a)
    - Belden Hill Road - Comstock house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 450)
    - 302 Belden Hill Road - Counterfeiting, 1907-1908 (Cabinet 2, Folder 530)
    - 11 Belden Hill Road - Deacon Daniel Gregory house, undated; Built 1775. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 460)
    - 180 Belden Hill Road - Ebenezer Gregory house, undated; Built circa 1714. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 510)
    - 160 Belden Hill Road - Ebenezer Gregory I house, undated; Built circa 1754. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 490)
    - 1 Belden Hill Road - Evans house, undated; Built before 1855. Remodeled circa 1919. (Cabinet 2, Folder 442)
    - 38 Belden Hill Road - Gregory house, undated; Built circa 1790. Remodeled 1940. (Cabinet 2, Folder 444)
    - 215, 217 Belden Hill Road - Gregory-Goldsmith house, undated; Built 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 515)
    - 169 Belden Hill Road - History by Helen Gregory, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 501)
    - 227 Belden Hill Road - James-Weeks house, undated; Built 1827. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 520)
    - 296 Belden Hill Road - Josiah Gilbert house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 525)
    - 468 Belden Hill Road - Justus Keeler house, undated; Built circa 1780. (Cabinet 2, Folder 547)
    - 368 Belden Hill Road - Knapp-Jenks house, undated; Built circa 1790. (Cabinet 2, Folder 543)
    - 169 Belden Hill Road - Matthew Gregory house, undated; Built circa 1740. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 500)
    - 242 Belden Hill Road - Nathan Gregory house, undated; Built circa 1779. (Cabinet 2, Folder 521)
    - 83 Belden Hill Road - Stewart-Westcott house, undated; Built between 1787 and 1796. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 480)
    - 432 Belden Hill Road - Theodore Smith house, undated; Built circa 1825. (Cabinet 2, Folder 545)
    - 359 Belden Hill Road - Vollmer house, undated; Built circa 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 542)
    - 83 Belden Hill Road - Westcott barn, undated; Built 1786. (Cabinet 2, Folder 485)
    - 4 Borglum Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 548)
    - 89 Borglum Road - Solon Borglum studio, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 549a)
    - 111 Branch Brook, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 549b)
    - 49 Cannon Road - Aaron Lockwood house, undated; Built circa 1865. (Cabinet 2, Folder 564)
    - 15 Cannon Road - Ambler house, undated; Built circa 1905. (Cabinet 2, Folder 553)
    - 175 Cannon Road - Baillie estate - Gardener's house, undated; Built 1927. (Cabinet 2, Folder 567)
    - Cannon Road - Cannon Grange - Building specifications, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 556b)
    - 25 Cannon Road - Cannon Grange hall, undated; Built 1899. (Cabinet 2, Folder 556a)
    - Cannon Road - Cannon store, undated; Built circa 1790. See also WHS Lambert Properties. (Cabinet 2, Folder 550)
    - Cannon Road - Cannondale railroad station, undated; Built 1892. (Cabinet 2, Folder 551)
    - 34 Cannon Road - Cannondale school house, undated; Built 1872. (Cabinet 2, Folder 561)
    - 20 Cannon Road - Godfrey Academy, undated; Established 1848. (Cabinet 2, Folder 554)
    - 37 Cannon Road - Godfrey house, undated; Built circa 1900. (Cabinet 2, Folder 562)
    - 26 Cannon Road - Gregory grist mill, undated; Built circa 1900. (Cabinet 2, Folder 557)
    - 30 Cannon Road - Gregory store and house, undated; Built circa 1900. (Cabinet 2, Folder 558)
    - 24 Cannon Road - Gregory store and post office, undated; Built 1850. Remodeled 1895. (Cabinet 2, Folder 555)
    - 32 Cannon Road - Gregory tenant house, undated; Built circa 1900. (Cabinet 2, Folder 559)
    - 63 Cannon Road - Hand house, undated; Built 1939. (Cabinet 2, Folder 565)
    - 109 Cannon Road - Hickok-Rounds house, undated; Built 1790. Remodeled 1910. (Cabinet 2, Folder 566)
    - 270 Cannon Road - Isaac Sterling house, undated; Built 1825. (Cabinet 2, Folder 569)
    - 226 Cannon Road - Jacob Patchen house, undated; Built 1731. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 568)
    - 320 Cannon Road - James Sturges house, undated; Built 1870. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 570)
    - 43 Cannon Road - Lockwood Academy, undated; Built circa 1851. (Cabinet 2, Folder 563)
    - 33 Cannon Road - Lockwood Brown Academy, undated; Built 1857. (Cabinet 2, Folder 560)
    - 8 Cannon Road - Nelson Hurlbutt house, undated; Built 1922. Remodeled 1981. (Cabinet 2, Folder 552)
    - 32 Catalpa Road - Louis Warncke house, undated; Built 1912. (Cabinet 2, Folder 571)
    - 64 Cedar Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 573)
    - 85 Cedar Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 574a)
    - 91 Cedar Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 574b)
    - 139 Cedar Road - David Platt house, undated; Built 1830. See also Oral History, Tape #40. (Cabinet 2, Folder 575)
    - 35 Cedar Road - Smith house, undated; Built 1850. (Cabinet 2, Folder 572)
    - 27 Center Street - Post office and store, undated; Built 1860. (Cabinet 2, Folder 579a)
    - 37 Center Street / Cottage Row - Carpenter-Bepler house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 577)
    - Center Street / Cottage Row - Gorham house, undated; Built circa 1890. (Cabinet 2, Folder 576)
    - Center Street / Cottage Row, Morehouse/Carpenter house, undated; Built 1888. (Cabinet 2, Folder 578)
    - 87 Charter Oak - Leo Rumley house, undated; Built 1936. (Cabinet 2, Folder 579b)
    - 46 Cheese Spring Road - Carpenter cottage, undated; Built 1910. (Cabinet 2, Folder 580)
    - Chestnut Hill Road - "Deserted house" (Finch), undated; Built circa 1890. (Cabinet 2, Folder 582)
    - 294 Chestnut Hill Road - Burr Wood house, undated; Built circa 1830. (Cabinet 2, Folder 595)
    - 36 Chestnut Hill Road - Dallett estate, undated; Built 1941. (Cabinet 2, Folder 585)
    - 306 Chestnut Hill Road - Ebenezer Abbott house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 597)
    - 2 Chestnut Hill Road - Ebenezer Coley house, undated; Built 1862. (Cabinet 2, Folder 584)
    - 156 Chestnut Hill Road - Gorham house, undated; Built 1840. (Cabinet 2, Folder 590a)
    - 120 Chestnut Hill Road - Gorham-Disbrow house, undated; Built 1831. (Cabinet 2, Folder 589)
    - 89 Chestnut Hill Road - Hanford house, undated; Built 1820. (Cabinet 2, Folder 588)
    - 61 Chestnut Hill Road - Jayne house, undated; Built 1830. (Cabinet 2, Folder 586)
    - 250 Chestnut Hill Road - John Gorham house, undated; Built 1910. (Cabinet 2, Folder 591)
    - 80 Chestnut Hill Road - Julia Brown house, undated; Built 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 587)
    - 223 Chestnut Hill Road - Trowbridge house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 590b)
    - 3 Church Street - Foster-Castle house, undated; Built circa 1890. (Cabinet 2, Folder 603)
    - 37 Church Street - Methodist Church of Georgetown, undated; Built 1830. (Cabinet 2, Folder 609)
    - 33 Church Street - Methodist Church parsonage, undated; Built circa 1875. (Cabinet 2, Folder 607)
    - 23 Church Street - Miller-Stromberg house, undated; Built circa 1915. (Cabinet 2, Folder 605)
    - 49 Church Street - St. John-Jennings house, undated; Built circa 1870. (Cabinet 2, Folder 610)
    - 1 Church Street - St. John-Rosendahl house, undated; Built circa 1860. (Cabinet 2, Folder 601)
    - Church Street (East) - Old Tory house, undated; Built circa 1760. (Cabinet 2, Folder 600)
    - 1 Collinswood - Holtvedt house, undated; Built circa 1830. (Cabinet 2, Folder 615)
    - Cottage Row, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 620)
    - 462 Danbury Road - Abraham Hurlbutt house, undated; Built 1819. (Cabinet 2, Folder 724)
    - 523 Danbury Road - Allee-White house, undated; Built circa 1820. (Cabinet 2, Folder 744)
    - 224 Danbury Road - Barn, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 676)
    - 387 Danbury Road - Basil Burt house, undated; Built circa 1923. (Cabinet 2, Folder 704)
    - 973 Danbury Road - Batterson-Kirla house, undated; Built circa 1820. (Cabinet 2, Folder 770)
    - 221 Danbury Road - Betts house, undated; See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 672)
    - Danbury Road - Betts-Harbs property, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 700)
    - 436 Danbury Road - Cannon-Miller house, undated; Built 1835. (Cabinet 2, Folder 718)
    - 196 Danbury Road - Charles Comstock house, undated; Built circa 1840 (Cabinet 2, Folder 652)
    - 487 Danbury Road - Charles Scribner house, undated; Built 1830. (Cabinet 2, Folder 732)
    - Danbury Road - Charles Whitlock house and school, undated; Built circa 1774 (Cabinet 2, Folder 624)
    - 237 Danbury Road - Chichester house, undated; Built circa 1873 (Cabinet 2, Folder 682)
    - 426 Danbury Road - David Henry Miller house, undated; Built 1907. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 716)
    - 150 Danbury Road - David Lambert house, Hurlbutt Street post office, and Kent school house, undated; Built circa 1724. Remodeled 1889. See also WHS Lambert Properties. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 650)
    - 218 Danbury Road - Eakland house, undated; Built circa 1880. (Cabinet 2, Folder 670)
    - 300 Danbury Road - Elijah Betts house (Crossways), undated; Built circa 1791. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 695)
    - 225 Danbury Road - Fillow-Ogden house, undated; Built circa 1841. (Cabinet 2, Folder 677)
    - 420 Danbury Road - Gagg house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 715)
    - 503 Danbury Road - George Nichols house, undated; Built 1830. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 740)
    - 51 Danbury Road - Gilbert-Shaw house, undated; Built circa 1920. (Cabinet 2, Folder 638)
    - 963 Danbury Road - Gustave-Carlson house, undated; Built 1916. (Cabinet 2, Folder 768)
    - 36 Danbury Road - Hanford house, undated; Built circa 1866. (Cabinet 2, Folder 634)
    - 763 Danbury Road - Hardej house, undated; Built circa 1923. (Cabinet 2, Folder 759)
    - 951 Danbury Road - Heibeck's, undated; Built circa 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 766)
    - 89 Danbury Road - Hickey house, undated; Built circa 1870. (Cabinet 2, Folder 644)
    - 387 Danbury Road - Hubbell house, undated; Built 1865. (Cabinet 2, Folder 706)
    - 490 Danbury Road - Hurlbutt-Keiser house, undated; Built circa 1790. (Cabinet 2, Folder 734)
    - 224 Danbury Road - James Betts house, "Deerfield house", undated; Built 1785. See also WHS Blackmar House, and PM, Notices, Auctions. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 675)
    - 20 Danbury Road - Jared Betts house, undated; Built circa 1825. (Cabinet 2, Folder 628)
    - 232 Danbury Road - Jerusha Holt house, undated; See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 680)
    - Danbury Road - John Betts house, undated; Built circa 1824. Southeast corner of Grumman Road. (Cabinet 2, Folder 622)
    - 530 Danbury Road - John Betts house, undated; Built circa 1739.See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 748)
    - 27 Danbury Road - John Dunning house, undated; See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 632)
    - 400 Danbury Road - John Goetjen house, undated; Built 1926. (Cabinet 2, Folder 708)
    - 555 Danbury Road - Jonathan Wood house, undated; Built circa 1706. (Cabinet 2, Folder 756)
    - 250 Danbury Road - Joseph P. Fitch house, undated; Built circa 1792. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 686)
    - 78 Danbury Road - Kenneth Lynch & Sons, undated; Established 1932. (Cabinet 2, Folder 642)
    - 475 Danbury Road - Lewis Hurlbutt house, undated; Built 1909. (Cabinet 2, Folder 728)
    - 261 Danbury Road - Lofink house, undated; Built 1927. (Cabinet 2, Folder 692)
    - 259 Danbury Road - Lofink-Whitehead house, undated; Built 1926. (Cabinet 2, Folder 690)
    - 405 Danbury Road - Marvin tavern, undated; See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 712)
    - 909 Danbury Road - Mead-Wolfe house, undated; Built circa 1825. (Cabinet 2, Folder 760)
    - 496 Danbury Road - Methodist Church parsonage, undated; Built circa 1845. (Cabinet 2, Folder 738)
    - 919 Danbury Road - Miller rental house, undated; Built 1880. (Cabinet 2, Folder 762)
    - 184 Danbury Road - Morehouse house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 651)
    - 454 Danbury Road - Nehemiah Reynolds house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 722)
    - 72 Danbury Road - Nelson Hanford house, undated; Built circa 1840. (Cabinet 2, Folder 640)
    - 481 Danbury Road - Noah Partrick house, undated; Built 1837. (Cabinet 2, Folder 730)
    - 213 Danbury Road - Orem farm, undated; Built circa 1875. (Cabinet 2, Folder 665)
    - 209 Danbury Road - Orem's Diner, undated; Established 1921. (Cabinet 2, Folder 660)
    - 923 Danbury Road - Peterson-Carlson house, undated; Built circa 1890. (Cabinet 2, Folder 764)
    - 415 Danbury Road - Samuel Betts house, undated; Built 1728. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 714)
    - 444 Danbury Road - Samuel Marvin house, undated; Built circa 1810. (Cabinet 2, Folder 720)
    - 198 Danbury Road - Sherman Morehouse house, undated; Built circa 1835. (Cabinet 2, Folder 655)
    - 224 Danbury Road - Sloan-Raymond-Fitch house / Wilton Historical Society Museum, undated; Built 1757. See also WHS. Formerly 249 Danbury Road. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 685a)
    - 254 Danbury Road - St. Matthew's Episcopal Church, undated; Built 1859. (Cabinet 2, Folder 688)
    - 713 Danbury Road - Stone Mill roadside market, undated; Built circa 1935. (Cabinet 2, Folder 758)
    - Danbury Road - Sturgeon-Gaylord house, undated; Built 1726. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 626)
    - 526 Danbury Road - Taylor Academy, undated; Established circa 1843. (Cabinet 2, Folder 746)
    - 532 Danbury Road - Taylor-O'Hayer barn, undated; Built circa 1890. (Cabinet 2, Folder 752)
    - 23 Danbury Road - The Dress Barn, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 630)
    - 516 Danbury Road - Thomas Cole house, undated; Built circa 1719. (Cabinet 2, Folder 742)
    - 238 Danbury Road - Town hall, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 683)
    - 354 Danbury Road - Whitney-Sterling house, undated; See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 702)
    - 539 Danbury Road - William Belden house (Egypt), undated; Built circa 1740. (Cabinet 2, Folder 754)
    - 493 Danbury Road - William Nichols house, undated; Built circa 1800. (Cabinet 2, Folder 736)
    - 39 Danbury Road - Wilson's hardware store, undated; Established circa 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 636)
    - 146 Danbury Road - Wilton railroad station, undated; Built 1852. (Cabinet 2, Folder 648)
    - 239 Danbury Road - Wilton town hall, undated; See also WHI, Town Hall. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 685b)
    - 116 Danbury Road - Wiswell-Yinkey estate, undated; Built circa 1895. (Cabinet 2, Folder 646)
    - 404 Danbury Road - YMCA director's home / Donaldson house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 710)
    - 470 Danbury Road - Zion's Hill Methodist Church, undated; Built 1844 (Cabinet 2, Folder 726)
    - 2 DeForest Road - Jeremiah Mead house / Mead's tavern, undated; Built 1726. See also PHO. (Cabinet 2, Folder 772)
    - 156 DeForest Road - Whelpley-DeForest house, undated; Built circa 1725. (Cabinet 2, Folder 780)
    - 6 Downe Lane - Downes house, undated; Built 1931. (Cabinet 2, Folder 785)
    - 19 Drum Hill Road - Daniel Trowbridge house, undated; Built circa 1750. (Cabinet 2, Folder 791)
    - 127 Drum Hill Road - Dickman-Canfield house, undated; Built 1875. (Cabinet 2, Folder 796)
    - 212 Drum Hill Road - Fromhart-Chapin house, undated; Built 1865. (Cabinet 2, Folder 802)
    - 165 Drum Hill Road - James Stuart house, undated; Built circa 1767. See also Nash family. (Cabinet 2, Folder 800)
    - 42 Drum Hill Road - Middlebrook estate, undated; Built 1927. (Cabinet 2, Folder 792)
    - 3 Drum Hill Road - Middlebrook house, undated; Built 1885. Remodeled 1932. (Cabinet 2, Folder 790)
    - 88 Drum Hill Road - Robert Dill house, undated; Built circa 1820. (Cabinet 2, Folder 794)
    - 149 Dudley Road - Ebenezer Jackson house, undated; Built 1726. (Cabinet 2, Folder 810)
    - 115 Dudley Road - Stevens house, undated; Built 1890. (Cabinet 2, Folder 804)
    - 2 East Meadow - Catherine Page Stone house, undated; Built 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 812)
    - 66 East Meadow - Karpf house, undated; Built 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 814)
    - 79 East Meadow - Paine house, undated; Built 1930. (Cabinet 2, Folder 816)
    - 86 East Meadow - Rickus house, undated; Built 1938. (Cabinet 2, Folder 818)
    - 18 Forest Lane - W. R. T. Smith house, undated; Built 1991. (Cabinet 2, Folder 819)
    - 5 Forge Road - Johnny Gruelle house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 820a)
    - General information, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 440)
    - 6 Godfrey Place - Goslee house, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 820b)
    - 14 Grumman Avenue - Grumman house, undated; Built circa 1790. (Cabinet 2, Folder 822)
    - 95 Grumman Hill Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 825)